I think there's a lot of fear about AI
outside [music] of Silicon Valley. I
understand why because it's changing
their job. It's displacing them. And
some of that may be true, but I am
saying that everyone has the power now.
>> This is Brian Chesy, co-founder and CEO
of Airbnb, a Fortune 500 company valued
at $95 billion. He believes AI is
widening the gap between people who have
access to the same tools. So I wanted to
understand what actually gives people an
edge in an AI powered world.
>> AI is like an amplifier. It makes the
good people [music] better and the
people that weren't as good, it's less
of a multiplier for them.
>> I'm just trying to translate this for
people who are thinking about different
business ideas. How do they know that
idea is viable to [music] launch?
>> This is what I would do.
>> This video is sponsored by HubSpot.
>> Hi Brian.
>> Hey, how you doing? Good to see you.
>> Welcome to Silicon Valley Girl. It's
been 7 years since we first met. And I
wanted to show you this. I don't know if
you remember, but that crazy girl at the
airport who saw Brian Chesy and then ran
to you.
>> Oh, yes.
>> And you were boarding a commercial
flight.
>> Of course. What airport was that?
>> It's LAX. Thank you for being so nice
and friendly.
>> Of course. Look at how well you're
doing. And I'm so honored to be on your
program.
>> Thank you. And I invited you to a
podcast back then. So, seven years
later, we're doing it. We're doing it.
Here we are. So I came to San Francisco
building a travel company and then we
were going through really hard times
during COVID and seeing you navigate at
those times really gave me inspiration
and strength and now we we're in this
new era uh of transformation which is
AI. So today I wanted to focus on how
you're transforming the company for the
AI era and I wanted to make it as
applicable as possible for people who
are maybe thinking of starting a
business in the AI era or maybe having
hard times as a professional because so
much is changing. So talk to me about
Airbnb becoming AI native. What does it
mean for guests and also I'm a host. I
have a place in Hawaii that we're
renting out through Airbnb. So what does
it mean for both sides of the table? I
think it really just means um
modernizing every touch point of the app
to be more intelligent, easier to use.
And so I'll give you some examples.
Let's say you were a guest. Before AI,
you do a normal search. You type in a
location and you get a bunch of results.
Now with AI, starting today, you can hit
a toggle and you can do AI search. It's
very natural, very much natural language
like typing into a chatbot. And then it
is a very intelligent search. So you can
say, I want to go to Paris. this weekend
with this number of people. I want this
kind of view and I want this kind of
architecture and it will not only serve
up all the results, but it will also
prefilter everything for you because
Airbnb is very much about filters and
controls. You see, the chat bots aren't
really great for shopping. Chat bots
aren't really good for travel. And the
reason why is they're textbased. They're
very hard to compare. You want things to
be very inspiration based and browse
based. You want it to be fun and
entertainment oriented. It's
multiplayer. So the average Airbnb
people, it's three people traveling. So
they have to be able to like share. You
have to be able to message a host. You
have to be able to have filters and you
got to be able to see like if I turn
this filter off, I get this home, but if
I add this filter back, I get that home.
So we had to find this interface that
wasn't a chatbot, but that felt
chat-like that you can start to have a
conversation with, but you didn't take
away the functionality people loved.
Then when you get to an Airbnb, we have
these AI generated highlights. So AI
basically will summarize the listing for
you. And these are really nice
personalized snippets. They're
personalized to you. So we can make the
listing literally written for you saying
this is why you will like this listing.
Then when you get to the bottom of the
page, if you have a question, you don't
even have to ask the host now. You can
literally ask the page and the listing
could answer things for you. You can
still message the host, but now you can
message. Then if you have a bunch of
listings, you want to compare them.
We've got an AI comparison feature tool
which makes it really smart and easy.
And one of the challenges people don't
realize and one of the problems with
chatbot is Airbnb is very much a
comparison shopping problem. Okay, I
like these 10 homes. This one's got a
pool. This one's got a a barbecue. This
one's got really high ratings. This
one's new. This one's a little more
expensive. This one's in a really good
location. How do I make decisions and
how do I compare side by side and how do
I call down? Then we have brand new maps
where I can starting in Paris, I can tap
and see information about each
neighborhood. Eventually, this is going
to roll out to a thousand different
cities around the world. And these are
just some of the features we have in the
guest side. On the host side, we're
going to make the app feel more and more
like an agent that can be your coach,
understand your goals, it can help you
price your listing. So, I think the
basic idea is that it's Airbnb is
getting smarter. Airbnb's whole app is
going to feel more like an agent. But
when I say agent, I don't mean a
chatbot. People when they hear agents
and chat bots, they think they're the
same thing. They're not. Agent is an
ideolution of an application. It's an
application that is more intelligent and
understands you and knows you and it
leverages the power of AI. A chatbot is
a user interface. And I think because
most agents are chatbots, we conflate
the two.
>> Yeah.
>> But they're not the same thing. And I
think that a chatbot is not the right
interface for travel. It's not the right
interface for um shopping, but agents
are great. And I think the great thing
about agents is they're interoperable.
So one agent can talk to another agent.
>> And so I think agents are definitely the
future of Silicon Valley and chatbots
are not.
>> Yeah. And chatbot feels like more like a
reactive thing where agent is more
proactive knowing your interests. And I
really like the comparison feature
because you don't know how many hours I
spent. She's like two very similar
bookings, but this one is quieter, but
this one has a bigger bedroom. And
you're like, having them side by side, I
think makes a huge difference. And
you're also adding a social graph,
something that I absolutely love.
>> You know, it's so funny. Um, I came to
Silicon Valley 19 years ago. Um, and
when I came to Silicon Valley, there was
this thing called a social network, and
it was Facebook, and everyone was on
Facebook, and it was mostly just your
friends, and you could keep in touch
with your friends, and they shared what
they did. And now none of my friends are
on Facebook. Um, and Instagram is not
social networking is social media. So
it's basically Instagram, X, YouTube,
Tik Tok. They're really not social
networks. They're really performance
platforms. They're broadcast platforms.
And this is not I'm not saying this is a
bad thing, but I'm saying now there's no
place in the internet for me to know not
only what my friends are doing, but one
of the things I used to like was knowing
where people were traveling. people in
my life, where have they traveled to?
Where are they going? And so, here's a
use case. Let's say I'm going to
Chicago. I'm sure I have a bunch of
friends been to Chicago, but I don't
know which ones. And now, if I connect
people on Airbnb, I can see all of my
friends have been to Chicago, and I can
see where they stayed. I might want to
stay where they've stayed, but more
importantly, I can ask them like, "Hey,
what's good to do in Chicago?" Because
what we found is increasingly people
want recommendations for their friends
and their family rather than from you
know celebrities or writers. They
increasingly want people who feel like
they know them. Like you know me, you'll
know what I like but this is unsolved
problem because you don't know where
everyone in your life has traveled.
Another thing about Airbnb is one of the
best parts of it is meeting somebody
new. You was hard to meet people today.
I asked my um my parents how did you
meet people? They would go to a mall.
They go to a theater. They go to
physical spaces. Increasingly, people
today are not in physical spaces.
They're on their phones. And phones are
really a way for you to talk to
strangers online, but it's a really hard
way to meet strangers offline. And so,
we want to help solve this problem by
making it easier to meet people in the
real world and stay in touch with them.
And so, if you travel, you stay in a
home with somebody, you might meet them.
If you go on experience with somebody,
you can stay in touch with them. So, I
think a lot of what we're trying to do
is turn Airbnb from a kind of just a
marketplace of homes to a little more of
a travel community. And I think the
travel graph is really cool. And if you
go on Airbnb, you can basically add your
friends, your family, and you can see
where they're traveling. And this is a
really cool use case. Wouldn't you be
curious to know where all your friends
are traveling this summer?
>> I think it's pretty cool.
>> Now, you can know and you can decide,
well, if they're going, we can go at the
same time.
>> Yeah. And uh one of the reasons I
started this podcast because I wanted to
meet people offline and whenever guests
suggest do an online thing, I'm like no
no no that's not the reason I wanted to
do that in the first place. So I can
totally relate and I think you're also
opening up uh opportunities for new
businesses, right? Cuz you're now doing
groceries, baby gear, um restaurant
deliveries. Is it 700 plus features that
you're launching?
>> I think so. Yeah, we're we we're
launching I think the stat is that we're
like shipping 80% more features than a
year ago. Most of it's because of AI.
Obviously, AI is like this incredible
superpower. You know, 10 years ago, even
a few years ago, everything had to be
coded by hand. Everything was so much
harder to do. Now that you can ship
things so much more quickly, we can ship
features more quickly. It used to take
us a year to ship like a new service,
now we can do it in weeks. And so now,
like for example, with services, one of
the things we hear from guests a lot is,
I love to stay in homes, but they don't
have all the services of a hotel. And we
thought, well, what if we could have not
only all the service hotel, but even
more services? So, we can have baby gear
if you have kids. You know, sometimes
hotels have cribs, but maybe they have
two cribs or three cribs. And if they're
out, you've got this is what we I don't
have kids, but I hear from from my
friends who have kids, maybe you want
laundry done. A hotel is laundry. Well,
now Airbnb, you can get laundry. So, we
just wanted to go down the list. Um, ski
rental equipment. I'm going to go
skiing. I don't want to I don't have my
own ski equipment. So going to rent ski
gear can be very very you know it can be
ownorous right and you just get to a
city you're tired you don't want to
figure out how to get ski gear we can
have all the sizes waiting for you all
the equipment for you so we're really
trying to make every as plugandplay as
possible so you're not just getting a
home you're kind of getting a full
service experience so eventually IC
adding dozens even hundreds of services
that can be plugged into the home so
that when you book a home you can get
everything you need for your trip
>> what do you see the biggest opportunity
for small businesses who are trying to
build to plug into your system.
>> Let's pretend I'm a masseuse. I'm a
masseuse in Tulum, Mexico. I'm just
making a random place up right now. How
do I get business? I only get business
from locals who know about me. But how
would I if a travel would I get
business? I probably wouldn't be able to
get business. Maybe I have to go work at
a resort and they have to give me
business. Now I can have my own
business. I can broadcast an Airbnb and
all the travelers coming to Tulum, if
anyone wants a massage, they can go on
Airbnb and they can book the massage
with me. So, kind of like the original
Airbnb where I had a home but no one
knew about my home and we gave them a
distribution platform and they could
basically get an audience. Kind of like
the way social media gives everyone an
audience, we can give all these small
business audiences and we give them a
global audience of travelers. And so,
this is really really difficult um for
somebody. I'm a photographer in Paris
and I take photos of families in front
of the EFL tower. A lot of people want
to get their photos. How do you get your
photo in front of the EFL tower? If
you're a parent, one of you is not in
photo
>> or you give the camera to someone else
and they're like being bothered
>> and it's just like an iPhone photo. Now
you can have like amazing professional
photos in 30 minutes. It's not too
expensive and you will remember those
photos forever. this photographer would
never have known how to broadcast to all
these guests from around the world. We
really feel like there's a whole economy
of service providers, whether there's
massuses, chefs, photographers,
companies that deal with equipment or
baby gear or laundry or cleaning
service, car rental, welcome pickups,
picking up the airport, anything you
imagine. In other words, now you can air
be more than just a home. You can air be
anything. If you're thinking about
starting a business, start with
something you already know how to do.
Well, maybe it's photography, catering,
or a service people keep asking you for.
Then you think about your first five
customers. How will you remember what
each person needs and what you promised?
Our sponsor, HubSpot, helps just with
that. It's new smart CRM is a CRM that
updates itself, keeping customer details
and conversations in one place. For
example, you finish a call about a
catering job. AI noteaker captures the
details, helps draft your follow-up, and
suggests next steps and updates to the
customer's record for you to approve so
you can spend more time delivering an
experience people want to recommend. If
you're ready to build something of your
own, explore HubSpot Smart CRM through
the link in the description. And thanks
to HubSpot for sponsoring this episode.
Now, back to Brian. And you were testing
all of these, I imagine, before
launching. Can you talk to me about all
the tests and what's the decision-m
criteria?
>> For everything we launch, we're probably
testing like many, many more things. And
we have dozens of services um underway.
So like ski equipment. I'm not a giant
skier, but um I ski a little bit. I
don't ski enough to have my own skis. I
don't ski enough to have my own boots,
my own helmet. So everywhere I go, I
have to rent equipment. And it's always
like I don't even know where to go. Do I
go to the mountain to rent equipment? Um
do I have to wait in line? I have to
wait for someone to size me. It's so
much more convenient if I were to get to
the Airbnb. They know my boot size, they
know my ski size, and they just have
everything for me. So, that is something
that we're testing. I think the test is
in Italy, but we're going to hopefully
bring this to ski mounds all over the
world. And there these ski rental
companies, and they would love to be
able to bring the equipment to you
rather than you have to wait in line at
the store, which is potentially really
inconvenient. surfing equipment. You
know, a professional surfer probably
will travel with their own surfboard,
but it's pretty hard to bring a
surfboard on an airplane, and a lot of
people aren't going to travel the
surfboard, and so they're going to have
to rent this equipment. What if in the
house waiting for you was this equipment
or you knew exactly where to go to get
the equipment? So, these are kind of the
ideas. So, we're trying to test, you
know, we usually do a test in one
market, one city. If it works, then we
bring it to other markets. And
everything we announced today, we've
been testing. So, we have a lot of other
services coming. There's literally
hundreds. By the way, the thing that's
exciting is the longtail. It's like
there's so many different services and
no one service maybe is big enough to be
a giant business that you've heard of
that has an app. So, that's the
challenge. Like ride sharing, there's an
app. Uber food delivery, there's an app.
Uber Eats, Door Dash. But most other
services aren't big enough to have a
global brand where you know where to go.
And even if they do have an app, they're
not integrated with Airbnb. And so it's
pretty difficult. Like Instacart, they
got an app, but now you can get
groceries at your Airbnb. And you have
an option where you can order the
Instacart groceries through the Airbnb
app. It already knows your address. It
already knows how many guests and the
food can be sent to the house and the
host can open the door and have the food
put in the fridge so it's stocked for
you. Amazing. It's just much more
convenient.
>> So, what is the criteria for launching?
I wonder if you have like internal
metrics. Is it like I don't know 10% of
guests are using the service? I'm just
trying to translate this for people who
are thinking about different business
ideas when they don't have access to
data like yours. How do they know that
idea is viable to launch?
>> It's a great question. I mean,
>> we started with the most popular
services um the most common ones, Chef,
masseuse, photography, car rental,
airport pickup, luggage storage. But
increasingly the power of Airbnb is the
idea that we want you to be able to
provide anything you can imagine. So my
hope is anything you offer if it could
be useful just to a couple people
visiting your city then we would love to
hear from you and I think just contact
Airbnb. I think you can there's a
contact button on the bottom of our page
and we try to intake as many ideas as
possible. So we have like a services
platform. Um, if you go to list, you
know, you can go to become a host.
There's a button you can basically apply
to become a services host. We might tell
you that this is coming soon, but we
take every single lead. So, let's say
you do like floral arrangements.
>> This is a use case. People are on
vacation. They're maybe on a romantic
trip. They want to get flowers in the
listing. Maybe they want flowers in the
listing. They want to get flowers for
the romantic significant other. That's a
service we're launching. And people can
apply. We don't have it in every city,
but if you have this idea, if you have
an idea like that, just apply. And if we
aren't ready to launch it now, we will
eventually. And so, it's just a matter
of getting to them. But we we want every
idea. I wouldn't want to tell people
what ideas to apply with because some of
the best ideas are ones I don't even
think of. But if you have something you
think is valuable to somebody else, you
just need an audience. And hopefully we
can give you that audience.
>> I love that. And I imagine shipping all
of these features became possible
because of AI. Do you have an internal
metric where you say, "Okay, AI is
adding that much to our productivity and
output versus just generating more stuff
that we're not using."
>> So the beginning of the year there was
this whole like token matching thing
where CEOs were telling everyone, you
got to use AI and they were measuring it
by how many tokens you were using and
there was a little bit of a initial
management philosophy to shame people
that didn't have a lot of tokens. There
were like token leaderboards. That might
have been a good thing to do for a
couple months just to make sure people
were using AI, but that was clearly like
a long-term strategy that was not going
to work. And now all of a sudden
everyone's like, "Wait a second. Why are
we spending so much money on AI?" And so
I think the most important thing is like
the customer doesn't care if we're using
AI to build their tools or not. They
just want the product to be better
faster. And so we look at product
velocity. How fast are you shipping? How
many features are you shipping? How
quick are you shipping them? Are they
high quality? And are they successful?
and we have metrics for that. So, we're
shipping 80% more features.
>> That is crazy, though. Just think about
80% more for a huge company like yours.
>> Yeah. And it's just two things. It's the
power of AI that suddenly um you don't
have to primarily code by hand. Um but
it's also cultural. People have to use
the tools and they have to use them
correctly. And it's amazing because AI
is the ultimate democracy. The tools
that Airbnb has is the tools every
company in the world has. We all have
access to the exact same tools. There's
really there's codeex, there's cloud
code. It's kind of like back in the day
I used Photoshop and I was a designer,
illustrator. We all have the same tools.
We all have these amazing tools, but
they're not equally distributed. The
very best people know how to like
immerse themselves and get the most out
of the tools. And so, one of the things
we tried to do is we tried to make sure
people learned how to use the tools
correctly. And there's no replacement
for like good thinking. You know, you
need to have like really good data. You
need to like still have good
collaboration. AI allows an idea to get
out of your head into the world faster,
but it doesn't necessarily give you
better ideas. You still have to be have
great ideas. You still have to have
great thinking. It's now about great
thinking. It's about great
understanding. It's about great
curiosity. And I think AI rewards deeply
curious people because you can do
endless iteration. AI is like an
amplifier. It makes the good people
better. and the people that weren't as
good, it's less of a multiplier for
them. So, I find that the um dynamic
range um the performance gap is greater
with AI that the really high performers
even better with AI. I'm a designer by
training. I went to Risie 19 years ago
when I started I couldn't code and today
I could code because I could prompt and
so suddenly in that way it is so
democratic. All of us can do so many
more jobs at the same time. Great
thinking, great taste, great
understanding, understanding user
problems. These are things that matter
even more now because it's no longer can
you build it. It's what do you build and
is should you build it and and does it
matter?
>> Quick tip to people who want to upgrade.
You were describing people who are at
the edge of productivity and generating
ideas and being curious. Is there is
this
>> I think there was a saying by this like
Nobel Prize winning uh maybe chemist
Lionus Pauling he said the best way to
have a good idea is to have a lot of
ideas like Airbnb seemed like a good
idea right it was one of many ideas and
we had a lot of bad ideas I think it's
about like sheer output the best way to
have a good idea is to have a lot of
ideas the best way to create a good
drawing is to create a lot of drawings
the best way to do anything is to create
a lot of it just through out sheer
output I mean you're really good. Now,
what you've done, you probably did it
through a lot of repetition, right?
There wasn't one moment where you got
good. Similar to exercise, you don't get
in shape in one workout. It's through
repetition. So, what I found is that the
very best people are the ones that just
practice more than anyone else and they
put in the repetitions. It working out
is actually a good metaphor. It's
repetition. And so, idea repetition
matters. You know, I know at IDO there's
there are a very famous design firm.
They used to do this exercise where the
way you generate ideas, they give every
people probably some people might know
this. They give you everyone post-it
notes and you have to write an idea
down, put a post-it note on the wall,
another idea on a wall. And they had a
rule. You can never critique ideas
initially. No devil's advocates, no
critiquing ideas because when you
critique your ideas, you edit your
thinking and you're afraid. And bad
ideas sometimes are one step away from a
good idea. And so I think it's all about
volume of ideas. I probably not
exaggerating have 100,000 ideas a year
and I think 99,000 are really bad.
>> Out of all the ideas, how do you know
which ones not to work on?
>> It's more the good ideas jump off the
page.
>> So for example, I basically have a
notebook and every thought is like a
sentence or a couple sentences and I
probably write maybe a thousand words a
day. So that's probably 300,000 words a
year. And maybe each line is a sentence
is like 10 words. So maybe that's a 100
ideas a day. So that's maybe 30,000
ideas a year. And so then what I do is
say I have 30,000 thoughts a year. 99%
of them are not useful, right? Just
something you write something down.
Anything that comes to your mind, I just
keep writing it down. At the end of
every day, I bold the things that jump
out at me. And so if I wrote down like a
hundred things, 100 lines, I bolded five
to 10. And then at each day, I bold
them. At the end of every month, I look
and my AI now can just read the bold
ideas. I used to have to manually like
pull out the ideas and read them. Now
the AI can pull out the bolded ideas.
The AI can also read and find ideas I
thought were stupid. It can tell me
really good ideas. it can see patterns
and then those become my short list and
then I iterate them, iterate them,
iterate them. You know, I think like
catching the rise 70,000 words and I
probably have like four times that
output in words and my writing is a
thousand times worse. It's really bad
writing. It's not high quality. Um, I'm
not writing like if you were to read it,
you'd be like, "This is borderline
nonsensical. It's understandable to me,
not to someone else." And I think that's
the point is that most my words are bad.
Most my ideas are bad. And it doesn't
matter because no one knows about the
bad ideas. They only need to know about
the good ideas. And here's the lesson.
Good ideas don't die. If you write
something down, you write a good idea
down, a month later you're going to
write the same idea down again. And you
won't realize it comes back.
[clears throat] So I find that good
ideas, they don't want to die. They kind
of stay alive and everything else just
kind of falls by the wayside. and these
good ideas, they kind of haunt you like
ghosts and you're like, "Okay, this this
thing's not going away." I don't know if
that's useful. I never said this before,
but I think it's about like just total
output. Just constantly I I remember um
hearing about Eminem. He would just
write all day. He had a notebook and
he'd write lyrics and rhymes all day.
Bob Dylan was just writing songs all the
time, just writing and writing and
writing and writing. Now, not everyone's
like that. Like Jay-Z apparently like
doesn't do that. He just like thinks in
his own head and like that's very unique
prodigious skill that he has. Leonard Da
Vinci, he left behind so many notebooks
and he was just drawing and writing and
drawing and writing. And by the way,
most of Da Vinci did was write, not
draw. If you look at his notebooks, it's
80% writing, 20% drawing. And he
[snorts] is the most famous painter of
all time. He had like 12 paintings ever.
Mona Lisa is one of 12 or 15 paintings
he ever painted. So think about the
sheer volume of stuff he created.
Vincent Van Gogh most of his
productivity was in the last three years
of his life and he painted more than one
painting a day every single day. And
this is in in addition to sketches he
just every day he wrote he wrote he
wrote Hemingway wake up at 6:00 a.m.
from 6:00 a.m. to noon he would just
write and he would write till he had
nothing left to write at noon. And it
was just it's this this discipline of
repetition. Whether you're a tech
founder, you're an artist, you're a
writer. It's about pure volume. It
doesn't mean you put out a lot of crap.
>> Like you don't publish it all.
>> Yeah.
>> You have to you you then you edit and
you edit and you only publish the very
best of your stuff. But I think that
what people don't understand is they
only see a few things go out and they
don't see the sheer volume of what goes
in. And I think the problem, and maybe
I'm going to admit to a problem I have,
and I think almost every single person
watching has, is we spend too much time
on social media paying attention to what
other people are doing.
>> My advice is X. And I like and most most
of us are on X or Twitter way too much.
And we're way too focused on what other
people are doing. Oh my god, now it's
Instinct, now it's Muse, and now it's
this, and now it's that. And there's
just we're all like kids chasing soccer
balls and we're all like trying to play
fast fashion, trying to copy what
everyone else is doing and just it's
just so distracting.
>> It is.
>> And I wonder if we'd all be better off
just like not being a little bit
ignorant to whatever else is going on in
the world. Part of me is like, you know,
Van Go couldn't doom scroll. And if he
could doom scroll, he might not have
painted so much. If Da Vinci could doom
scroll, he might not have had so much
output. And if all of us could just
block out a bit more of what everyone
else is doing and say it doesn't really
matter what people think. Or even if you
do care what people think, let people
value you years from now. See, I'm going
to put blinders on and I'm just going to
just dig in and I'm going to work for
years and I'm not going to worry about
getting attention now. I will earn
attention later if it matters to me, but
I'm going to practice quietly and I
don't need the world to watch me
practice. I'm going to quietly practice.
I want to become great at my craft and
when I'm ready I'm gonna put something
out there. I think that would be so
valuable. We're just put blinders on and
just lock in and just go.
>> I think this is such valuable advice,
such great practice. We need to be doing
more of cuz
>> and I and I I admit I'm giving advice to
others and I have to keep reminding it
of myself. Stop worrying about whatever
else is going on in Silicon Valley.
focus on it's so hard and you don't want
to be naive like you want to know
generally if you're a comp company you
want to know what's going competition
you want to know what's late the latest
with AI developments but you can do that
like 10 minutes a day you don't need to
do that 2 three hours you don't need to
open X or YouTube or Instagram or
whatever your platform dour is 17 times
or 25 times this is what I would do and
I don't do it as much but I wish I did
it once a day for like 20 30 minutes I'm
going to go on whatever platform I go
on, I'm going to learn. Okay, now I'm
done. And then this time is
uninterrupted and I'm going to like not
have my phone on. By the way, the phone
spend more time in a computer, less time
on a phone.
>> The computer is the ultimate tool. We
designed phones on computers. We don't
design computers on phones.
>> The phone was never designed to be
something you stare at all day.
>> When Steve Jobs designed it, his vision
wasn't you're on it all day. Long
attention span stuff should be reserved
for big screens. So you should not be
staring at a phone very long because
what it does is it trains your dopamine
to multitask and to like change things.
And it what it does is it like the phone
is an enemy to focus and it's not
designed to be something you're staring
at for hours a day. The computer is
great for focus. A large screen. The
bigger the screen, the longer your
attention span. That's why if you go to
like an IMAX theater, you're not going
to go to the bathroom.
>> You own in a living room, you watch a
television show, you might get up on
your computer, you'll watch a YouTube
film, but on a phone, you only be able
to pay attention for 15 seconds before
you scroll to the next video. Attention
span is commensurate with screen size.
>> I never thought about that.
>> If you want to focus, you need to have a
long attention span. If you want to have
a long attention span, you need to have
a big screen. Do not look at a phone if
you want to focus.
>> You mentioned having so many ideas. If
you were not building Airbnb today in
the AI era, what would you be building?
>> I used to think I was I I was lucky
because I was 26 when I came to Silicon
Valley. And when I came to Silicon
Valley, the iPhone had just launched.
Facebook was like blowing up. YouTube
was out. The internet was going global.
Cloud computing meant like you could
have an app and not have to buy your own
servers. What it meant was it was kind
of easy to start a company. And there
was this iPhone that was distribution.
And so suddenly you could just put in an
app store and everyone could discover
it. I felt like I was the luckiest
person alive because I happened to be
born at the right place at the right
time. And it was just as much luck as
talent that I got to where I am today
because I just happened to be here at
this magical time in in history. And I
remember saying for years until the
launch of a of generative AI chubbyt I
said thank god I was born the time I did
because now is a tougher time. And then
post chatbt, part of me said, I wish I
was 26 again.
>> Because actually, as amazing as Airb is,
if I was 26, I could probably do
something just as cool because the tools
now are so much more powerful. I don't
know what I would do. I'm very
interested in education. I think AI can
transform education. I think content,
like you could build an AI Disney, you
could create incredible storytelling
with AI. Um, I think health is like an
incredible area. I think that like
instinct and muse are the beginning of
consumer AI, agentic AI, but I do not
think that the messaging
interface is the right interface to do
most work.
>> And so I would encourage entrepreneurs
to imagine other interface
modalities
>> like audio or even further
>> way further. We're visual creatures.
We're not most people are not textbased.
Why is Tik Tok more popular than
Twitter? Because it's video and visual.
I think that's the main reason. I don't
think it's any other reason. I think
that, you know, increasingly people are
visual. And I think a lot of
entrepreneurs are trying to fit this
technology that's the most powerful
technology in human history into a
messaging platform. It's like putting a
jet engine on the back of a bicycle.
>> We're just starting out. I guess
>> we're just starting. This is not to say
these apps aren't amazing. Here's
another way of saying it. Enthropic
opening are these giant companies.
There's going to be 50 more anthropics,
maybe hundred.
>> You think so?
>> I know. So, this is a cognitive
revolution. If people are watching,
there going to be so many companies that
are going to be bigger than Airbnb,
bigger than Anthropic. There's not this
like AI window. There's not this. We're
not in a cycle. We're not in a window.
And if we are, it's a thousand-year
window. You see, if technology doubles
every year for 10 years, that's a
thousandx.
So, let's say we're at the beginning of
a thousand-year cycle. If we're the
beginning of thous cycle, why do you
think there's just going to be two big
companies? There's going to be so many
huge companies emerge, but also there's
going to be tens of millions or millions
of small companies emerge because
suddenly one, two or three people can
start a whole business. It was
inconceivable before. I think AI is You
know, I think there's a lot of fear
about AI outside of Silicon Valley. I
understand why because I think people
outside of Silicon Valley feel like AI
is happening to them and that someone
else has it and it's happening to them
and it's changing their job. It's
displacing them. And some of that may be
true and I'm not defending it.
>> But I am saying that
>> everyone has the power now and that if
you have an idea, you can now make
something. And it is so much easier to
build a company now than it was 20 years
ago. I'm really proud of what I built,
but the next generation of people
watching are going to build things way
better than I ever dreamed of because
they have tools I never had.
>> This is so inspiring. Brian, can you
tell me in 10 seconds the process that
they all have to try in order to realize
the power of AI? Something that
transformed the way you work.
>> I think it's like jumping in a pool. I
was, for example, and this has been more
than 10 seconds, but I was like
intimidated to try Claude Code
>> and I just like didn't know how to
start. I mean, I had an employee who was
really good at it and I said like,
"You're going to tutor me." Now, not
everyone watching has an employee that
can tutor them. But everyone either you
know more than all your friends about AI
or someone knows more about it than you.
If somebody knows more about it than
you, like have them help you. I mean,
YouTube's an incredible resource. And I
just think like just start.
>> Just jump in the pool.
>> It's jump in the pool. And it is the
water is not cold. It just looks cold.
For those that are already in the pool,
just don't get out.
>> Thank you so much, Brian. Thank you for
being as amazing as you are.
>> Well, thank you for being amazing.
>> If you want to stay updated on all the
things these founders say here, we take
the use cases and prompts from every
conversation and put them into my
newsletter called Future Proof. And of
course, we also put my own beautiful use
cases there. For example, we put
together the seven skills that came up
again and again, the ones people will
need in the next few years. These are
the skills that my team and I are also
using daily. Subscribe through the link
in the description. You'll get that one.
And you can also read our previous
newsletters and see what you missed.